Glen Harding

Email: Glen.Harding.nz@gmail.com, Mobile: 02102972471, Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/glen-harding-5a1317114,

GitHub: https://github.com/nelg62, Portfolio: https://nelg62.github.io/

CAREER SUMMARY

With 5+ years of experience in the tech industry, I have honed my skills in troubleshooting issues and providing technical assistance to end-users both onsite and remotely. I have completed an AUT-accredited Certificate in Software Engineering, where I gained practical skills in designing and implementing software solutions. I am eager to begin my career as a developer and am looking for a junior role to get started. Key workplace skills I bring to an organization include a deep understanding of end-user needs, strong troubleshooting abilities, and a willingness to learn guickly.

KEY SKILLS

- Front-end development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Figma, Bootstrap, MUI
- Back-end and web develop: Node.js & React
- Database design: MongoDB, MySQL, Redis
- API development
- Software deployment

- Communication and collaboration
- Technical aptitude
- Creative, with end user in mind
- Growth mindset and desire to learn
- Critical and analytical thinking
- Project and time management

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2023 - 2024

AUT/Institute of Data

Software Bootcamp - Professional Certificate in Software Engineering

- Software Development Principles
- API Development and Integration
- Javascript Programming
- Front End Development
- Back End and Full Stack Development
- Interactive Web Design
- Web Design with React II

Mini Projects:

- Mini Project 1: https://github.com/nelg62/Module-4/tree/master/MiniProject1
- Mini Project 2: https://github.com/nelg62/MiniProject2
- Mini Project 3 (Group Project): https://github.com/nelg62/MiniProject3

Capstone Project

: https://github.com/nelg62/CapstoneProject

2017 - 2017

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 7 Diploma in Cloud Management in Information Technology

- Install, upgrade, migrate, configure & troubleshoot Windows Client OS
- Configure & install DNS, WINS, DHCP, network infrastructure & servers
- Configure Active Directory in Windows Server Identify, protect, authenticate & asses network security & basic Cryptography
- Use MDT & SCCM for Deployment

2016 - 2016

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 6 Diploma in Networking and Security in Information Technology

- WDS, MDT Deployment
- Installing and Configuring Windows Server 2012
- Administering Windows Server 2012
- Configuring Advanced Windows Server 2012 Services

2015 - 2015

Techtorium NZ Institute of Info Tech

Level 5 Diploma in PC Support in Information Technology

- PC Hardware & Software Installation, Repair & Support
- Networking Concepts and Server Administration
- Internet & Networking Security, WAN & LAN Security
- Windows Applications, Operating Systems, and Web-Creation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Foundation Partners Limited May 2023 - Current

Level 1 & Level 2 Service Desk Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Provide first and second level ICT support to customers at medium to large businesses
 - o Predominantly via phone assistance
 - Occasional on-site visits as required
- Collaborate with other team members to deliver support services
- Assist clients as needed with various ICT issues
- Follow directives from Senior Engineers or Senior Managers for on-site assistance
 - o Diagnose ICT issues on-site
- Communicate proactively with end-users and directing engineer/manager
 - Update status of projects or requests to end-users and supervisors
- Proficient in utilizing various software solutions to troubleshoot and resolve issues effectively:
 - 3cx
 - TeamViewer
 - N-central
 - Halopsa

Fusion Tech Limited June 2019 - May 2023

ICT Support Technician

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshoot IT issues for small to medium-sized businesses, including server management.
- Set up mobile phones, laptops, and other devices.
- Proficient with software and tools such as Office 365, Sophos routers, and Acronis.
- Knowledgeable in:
 - Azure
 - Sharepoint
 - Nagios
 - Shadowprotect
 - Scalefusion
 - o Eset
 - Yealink PBX and phone systems.
- Work on a helpdesk, including using a ticketing system and taking phone calls.
- Provide on-site IT support
- Work independently and as part of a team.
- Willing to learn new technologies and software to stay up-to-date with industry advancements.
- Use Active Directory to create and manage users and groups.

ICT Support Technician

Responsibilities:

- Provide on-site IT support for small to medium-sized businesses and individual clients.
- Troubleshoot IT-related issues for both Mac and iPhone-based devices.
- Fix hardware and software issues for Mac devices.
- Use backup and cloning tools such as Time Machine and Shadow Protect.
- Set up Android and iPhone phones, as well as Mac laptops.
- Install OS and recover lost data.
- Understand how companies and individuals use their devices and troubleshoot issues accordingly.
- Work independently and as part of a team.
- Learn new technologies and software to stay up-to-date with industry advancements.

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I have always been fascinated by technology. Seeing new devices and software excites me, as it fuels my curiosity to try them out and understand how they work. My recent acquisition of programming skills has unlocked numerous possibilities for creating and accomplishing projects I've always dreamed of. This journey into programming has not only broadened my horizons but also equipped me with the tools to innovate and bring my ideas to life.